Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nguyen-thiphuong-nhi-sophia-2889b2175 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

People Management
Problem solving and lean expert
Data Analysis

Certifications

Project Management Professional (PMP)

Publications

Never give up

Nguyen Thi Phuong Nhi (Sophia)

Asst. Project Manager @ TTI | PMP, Industrial Engineering Biên Hòa, Dong Nai, Vietnam

Summary

With 10 years of experience in leading and managing product development projects, I am a certified project management professional (PMP). I have worked for global corporations in various industries and countries, such as Intel, Sonion, and TTI Vietnam.

Currently, I am an Assistant Product Project Manager at Techtronic Industries Vietnam, where I collaborate with relevant stakeholders to plan, execute, monitor, and launch new products into the market. My core competencies include project managemenr,problem-solving, data analysis, lean manufacturing, and technical leadership. My mission is to deliver high-quality products that meet customer needs and expectations, and to contribute to the growth the company.

Experience

Techtronic Industries Vietnam Asst. Product Project Manager July 2022 - Present (2 years 9 months) Vietnam

Sonion Vietnam
Senior Project Leader
February 2021 - July 2022 (1 year 6 months)
Vietnam

Leading the Project Management Team to running projects. Working with relevant stakeholders (Engineering team, RnD, Sourcing, Quality, Purchasing, Key Account manager, Supplier, CQS...) to development, alignment, execution and monitor to launch new products into market. Plan, identify resource plan, project schedule, project budget, risk assessment from initial to project closure. Leading and guiding the team to solve problem to make sure project are meet requirement management.

Intel Corporation

7 years 5 months

Product Development Team Lead

January 2019 - February 2021 (2 years 2 months)

Vietnam

Leading and managing projects of new products and technologies are complete on time, above and beyond the department goals. Identify issues, and work cross-organizationally to resolve problems. Plan and manage technical programs/projects to meet established objectives or goals.

Achievement:

- Successfully leading 2 new products in 2020.
- Flawless execution to manage new product program. Driving to solve multiple issue and provide mitigation plan to support program smoothly.
- Deliver new product above and beyond product heath indicator which helps to gain tool capacity.

Product Development Engineer

February 2017 - December 2018 (1 year 11 months)

Vietnam

Performing evaluation and debug of new test program. Resolving product/ manufacturability issues related to product testing hardware and software. Performing data analysis and deploying solutions to improve test coverage, yield, hardware capacity, and other product health indicators. Development and debug of support software to support test program validation, data analysis and test debug.

Achievement:

- Engaged into 3 new products start up in Intel Vietnam
- Driving to achieve quality from customer requirement.
- Driving to solving issue from hardware and help to stable new line.

Process and equipment engineer

October 2013 - February 2017 (3 years 5 months)

Vietnam

Process Equipment Engineer

- Teamwork with members from different countries to resolve common issue and to evaluate, implement improvement opportunities.
- Provide technical support in problem solving and troubleshooting testing machine during High Volume Manufacturing.
- Do engage in oversea training for new product, machine and technology
- Provide training to technicians and equipment specialists to sustain tool health and performance during 24/7 manufacturing

Page 2 of 3

Education

University of technology and education Ho Chi Minh city

Bachelor's degree, Industrial Engineering · (September 2009 - October 2013)